English, I'm Alex Villareal.
This is the VOA Special English Technology Report.
Sony officials held a news conference in early May in Tokyo.
They apologized for the theft of personal information from millions of users of the
company's online services. Hackers targeted Sony's PlayStation Network, Sony
Online Entertainment, and Curiosity Music Systems. In all, Sony says information may
have been stolen from more than 100 million accounts. The data includes
information like names, addresses, phone numbers, and birth dates. In some cases, even
credit and debit card numbers may have been stolen. The United States Federal
Bureau of Investigation is looking into the cyber attacks. Sony shut down its
PlayStation Network on April 20th. The company is being criticized for not telling
its users about the stolen information until a week later. Sony has also been
criticized for not making its accounts more secure by encrypting the data.
Sony officials say they have now taken steps to improve security. Peter Warren is
chairman of the Cyber Security Research Institute in London. His group studies
technology crimes and their effects on our computer-dependent world. Mr.
Warren points out that what happened at Sony is not rare. We've seen a number of
very large companies that have suffered some tremendously embarrassing losses of
data. The problem, he says, is that there is far more interest in developing
technology than in keeping it safe. As he puts it, lots and lots of people are
being allowed to connect a lot of technology up before it's really been
particularly well tested. Peter Warren also points out that many people have
a false sense of security online. On the internet, he says, they seem to be so
blindly trusting of anybody and of any website, no matter how suspicious it may
look. His message to users is simple. Try to be more careful on websites. He
says, the internet is just like any other street and there are some twists and
turns that can take you into some very, very unsavory places. For VOA Special
English, I'm Alex Villareal. To read and listen to more technology news and
for English teaching activities, go to voaspecialenglish.com. You can also follow
us on Twitter and like us on Facebook at VOA Learning English.